And right now, there is so much at stake in these midterms.
We don't have the court to look out for the needs about equality and justice and fairness and freedom.
We don't have an executive branch who is doing much beyond attacking all those rights.
But while we can hold on to a democracy, we do have that third branch, which is Congress.
Which, if we can win even one half of it, we can have some of the guardrails to stop the pain.
And if we're only focused on 28, we're losing a lot of folks who need to be seen and, dare I say, protected.
So the guardrails, the guardrails couldn't have been put up when they had the majority of Congress for Biden's term.
They didn't have no guardrails they could put up then.
Let me tell you some of the guardrails that could have been put up.
First of all, they could have expanded the Supreme Court.
So her whole narrative about, oh, we don't have an executive branch and we don't have a judicial branch that can save us or that can care about us.
Well, when you had the executive branch, you did not use that role to expand the judicial branch.
The Supreme Court has been what it has been from the beginning of this country, which is simply not practical considering the expansion of this country.
And then anytime you see some shit that's not practical, I want you to know that it's not because these people are too dumb to know.
It's because there is a specific reason why they want it that way.
They want to remain in that they want it to remain this way because they can control it this way.
Other guardrail, Obama could have been, could have been made Roe versus Wade a law that was a part of the Constitution and not simply just something that can be flipped and flat, smack it up, flip it, rub it down, switch around whenever they want to.
He could have been did that.
Didn't do it.
Codified, ratified, I can never remember which word, but one of them, one of the fides could have been done and it didn't happen.
Same with Joe Biden.
So we're talking about guardrails.
All right.
What about the filibuster?
The filibuster has the option of being applied every session of Congress.
They are given the opportunity to put in a filibuster, which allows for the opportunity to extend the time within which a bill is passed to give the opposing party the opportunity to gather votes, to organize, to strategize, etc.
The Democrats stay saying, nah, we're good on that filibuster.
The Republicans ask for it every time.
So I just say all that to say that this is yet another example of pretending that they are going to do something for you and acting as if their only opportunity to help you is reactionary when there have been opportunities to be proactive.
So you have to ask yourself, why are the people telling me that they care about me constantly choosing not to be proactive about doing so?
And then you got to ask yourself, why do you keep supporting them if that's how they're behaving?
I'll be talking more about this on my radio show, Summer of Seals.
You can listen at KBLA Talk 1580.
It's Tavis Smiley's network.
So support the brother, support me and support yourself.
Download the app and take a listen.